Mousa Moradi Kondelaji

Software Engineer / Android Developer



+98(914)492-1058

stackoverflow.com/story/mousa-moradi

• Tehran, Iran in linkedin.com/in/mousa-moradi/

Summary

I am a software engineer with more than 10 years of experience in Desktop, Web, and Mobile application development. My current career and speciality is mainly Android development.

I am a team player; I am always learning new technologies, languages, and concepts; I adhere to software engineering principles and best practices in order to produce clean code and high-quality software.

Work Experience

Android Developer

at Sheypoor

Jan. 2019 - Present

▼ Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor provides classified advertisements website and mobile apps for goods and services. It is one of the two main market holders in Iran. The main Android app is installed and used by more than 5 million users.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Development of new features, most notably a fully-featured internal XMPP chat client, which connects to an XMPP server with the help of Smack library and enables users to chat with each other directly
- Writing and maintaining automated tests. These tests cover most of the app's code-base and have almost full
 coverage on crucial parts like data and domain layers. These tests help us later for preventing unwanted changes to
 existing code, by detecting failures early and easily
- Tracking issues and fixing bugs. I monitor Firebase Crashlytics service daily, and whenever a new issue started spiking, I worked quickly to solve it, test, build and deploy a fix. In that regard, we never had a critical situation for more than a couple of hours. This resulted in increased crash-free metric from 99.2% to 99.94%
- Improving code-base by rewriting to Clean Architecture, converting java to Kotlin, and introducing DI framework, which increased maintainability and testability
- · Conducting code reviews, doing pair-programming and mentoring new developers

Languages, technologies, and concepts used:

Java, Kotlin, RxKotlin, Retrofit, OkHttp, Glide, MVP, MVVM, Clean Architecture, JUnit, Mockito, Smack, GreenDao, Room, Git, Github-flow, Gitlab-flow, Dagger, LiveData, ViewModel, Firebase, Scrum, Jenkins

Android Developer

at Takhfifan

🛗 Apr. 2016 - Nov. 2018

• Tehran, Iran

Takhfifan is a Groupon-like company based in Iran and it is the leading in the Iranian market. I was the sole Android developer in this company, responsible for its two Android applications.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Development of new features, including nearby service discovery, easy app-to-app coupon invalidation, easy checkout procedure and many more.
- · Feasibility analysis and mock-up creation of newly proposed features
- Tracking issues and fixing bugs. I was able to increase the crash-free metric of the main app from 98.5% to 99.7% at the end
- Writing automated tests and performing manual tests. I increased code coverage from 0 to about 40% covering most of the crucial and critical sections
- Improving code-base by introducing new libraries to legacy code (Retrofit, Dagger, RxKotlin), refactoring from noarchitecture to MVP, and converting from Java to Kotlin, which led to increased maintainability and testability
- Developing a <u>new application (for business partners)</u> by applying TDD and having full test coverage
- Mentoring new developers and interns, supervising the iOS developer, and performing code reviews
- I was the Scrum Master of the development team for more than a year
- I was also a full-time Product Owner for two months
- During my time, the main app grew from 150,000 users to 500,000

Languages, technologies, and concepts used:

Java, Kotlin, Volley, Retrofit, OkHttp, Picasso, MVP, JUnit, Mockito, Espresso, Realm, Git, Git-flow, Dagger, Firebase, Scrum, Google Maps, OpenStreetMap

Android Developer / Symbian Developer

at Pactos

🛗 Aug. 2011 - Mar. 2016

▼ Tehran, Iran

I developed more than 10 mobile applications in this company which targeted blind users. Most of them were developed at first for Symbian OS and then for Android.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Development of a Persian TTS (Text-to-Speech) software for Symbian OS, using Symbian C++, which allowed synthesizing Persian texts to voice, and was the first such service in Symbian ecosystem
- Development of a Text/Audio book player for Symbian OS, using the Qt framework. This application reads and plays
 e-books in Daisy format
- Development of an Input Method Service (IME) for Android OS. This app enables blind users to input texts anywhere
 in Android, using invented simple sketch alphabet which is inspired by Braille alphabet, so it's easy and intuitive for
 blind users to learn and use it; I really enjoyed on designing a new alphabet, implementing sketch recognition and
 working on all other unique challenges
- Development of the same Daisy book player for Android OS
- Development of a Driver for the company's proprietary Braille Monitor for Android OS, using C language.
- Porting an existing Text-to-Speech engine of Windows OS to Android OS, using Android NDK
- Development of a File Reader app for Android OS, which is able to open many kinds of Text files and synthesize their contents to voice, using the company's proprietary TTS.
- Converting Symbian C++ code to Qt C++, and Java to Kotlin

Languages, technologies, and concepts used:

C, C++, Java, Kotlin, Qt framework, Symbian framework, Android framework, SVN, Git, MVC, JUnit, Mockito, Android NDK, Android TTS, Android IME, Android BrailleBack, Android TalkBack, Android Bluetooth

Skills and Tools

Object Oriented Programming

Object Oriented Design, Design Patterns, SOLID Principles, Architectural Patterns (MVC, MVP, MVVM, Uber RIBs), Clean Architecture, Refactoring Patterns

Programming Languages

Java, Kotlin, C++, and *familiar with* Objective C, Swift, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Ruby, Python

Testing

Unit, Functional, Integration, and, Acceptance testing, JUnit, Test Driven Development, Espresso, Mockito, and *familiar with* MockK, IMockit. and PowerMock

Frameworks

Android, Qt, and familiar with Symfony

Version Control

Git, SVN, CVS

Database

SQL, MySQL/MariaDB, SQLite, Room, Realm, GreenDao, and *familiar with* MongoDb, PostgreSOL

Methodology

Scrum, XP, Kanban, RUP

Reactive Programming

RxJava, RxKotlin

Android

Retrofit, Dagger, LiveData, ViewModel, Lifecycle, Smack, and *familiar with* Volley, Firebase components, KOIN, NDK

Functional Programming

Kotlin Standard Library, and familiar with Arrow

Operating System

Linux, Windows

Languages

English Fluent
Persian Native
Azerbaijani Native
Esperanto Advanced
Turkish Intermediate

Web Developer / System Ad	min	
at the Sharif University of Te	echnology 🖺 Sep. 2014 – March.	2016 • Tehran, Iran
As part of my mandatory service for the country, I worked at this university and maintained its websites.		
Responsibilities and achievements: • Maintaining the university's main website and more than 30 smaller departmental and institutional websites • Development of another website for automating new students' registration process, which reduced more than 95% of the manual effort of both students and staff		
Languages, technologies, and concepts used: Liferay CMS, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, CherryPy, LDAP, MongoDB		
iOS Developer		
at <u>Medopad</u>	igun. 2015 - Aug. 2015	• Tehran, Iran (Remote for London, UK)
I worked remotely for this company. My role was to create automated tests for its existing iOS application.		
Responsibilities and achievements: • Writing automated unit tests and end-to-end tests for the existing application • The result test coverage was more than 93% and 8 defects were found during the test suite creation period alone		
Languages, technologies, and concepts used: Objective C, iOS framework, OCMock, MVC		
Web Developer / Embedded software Developer		
at <u>Raymand</u>	Sep. 2010 - Nov. 2011	• Tehran, Iran
This company produces various GIS-related devices and equipment and I worked as a Software developer, creating different applications for those devices.		
Responsibilities: Contributing to the development of a Server application for gathering data and tracking distributed devices, using Qt framework and C++ language Creating an embedded HTTP server using Wt framework and C++ language		
Languages, technologies, and concepts used: C++, Wt framework, Qt framework, PHP, HTML, CSS, Protocol buffers		
Desktop Application De	eveloper	
at <u>Sarina System Sharif</u>	Aug. 2018 - Jul. 2019	• Tehran, Iran
I spent my internship at this company. I was partnered with another developer and together we created a Desktop client of a Fleet-tracking system.		
Languages technologies or	-d	

 $Languages, \, technologies, \, and \, concepts \, used: \,$

C#, .NET framework, SQLite, MySQL, RPC, Google Maps, Crystal Reports

Education

2011-2013 Sharif University of Technology M.Sc Software Engineering B.Sc 2006-2011 Sharif University of Technology Software Engineering

(Sharif University is the number one university of Iran and ranks $5^{\rm th}$ in the Middle East)

Honors and Awards

Ranked among 0.001 top participants of the national university entrance exam. (Rank 406 out of 500K) – 2006 $Ranked\ among\ 0.001\ top\ participants\ of\ the\ national\ graduate\ university\ entrance\ exam.\ (Rank\ 10\ out\ of\ 10K)\ -\ 2011$